Ryan Hatamosa

Full-Stack Software Engineer

 $301 - 323 - 5480 \cdot pinoydol.colada@gmail.com \cdot Beltsville, \ MD \cdot \underline{https://ryanhatamosa.vercel.app/} \cdot \underline{/in/ryan-hatamosa/} \cdot \underline{github.com/PinoyColada}$

I'm a growth oriented and creative software engineer who specializes in building full-stack applications. Being an analytical problem solver, I am driven by the idea of constantly facing new challenges within the ever-changing field of technology. My love for programming elevates my projects from assumptions to facts and my code to real-world solutions. My collaborative nature and background in management enable me to become a valuable member of any team.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Mongo, JSON, Postgres, Java | Database - PostgreSQL, MongoDB Libraries and Frameworks - React, Next.is, React Native, Express.is, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Portfolio Website | Next.js, Tailwind CSS

- A portfolio website showcasing my projects, skills, and information about me.
- Used Next.js for development and Tailwind CSS for styling, deployed through Vercel

Body Sculptor | MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js

- An application that tracks daily workouts by allowing users to record their work out routine.
- Made RESTful API fetch calls to an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and tested all backend routes during development using Insomnia.
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections and deployed the application through Heroku.

Coder Typer | HTML, CSS, Javascript

- A game where users complete typing tests of various code snippets as fast as possible.
- Developed a HTML/CSS based page layout with Flexbox and incorporated Regex in Javascript.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern, Amotions, Inc. | Burlingame, CA

August 2022 - October 2022

- Help developed and maintain a web application that is deployed on Netlify using React, Next.js and Chakra UI for the frontend and Firebase for the backend. The application helps people in management improve their soft skills.
- Coordinated with other back-end and front-end engineers to deliver products on schedule.
- Have stand up meetings every week to brainstorm and implement ideas and feedback into the app's development.

Package Dispatch Supervisor, UPS | Laurel, MD

April 2018 - August 2022

- Record route modifications to keep plans up-to-date and oversee load modifications to improve service and reduce costs.
- Develop, update, and monitor dispatch processes and plans using trend and production report data to adjust UPS driver routes.
- Trained and supervised drivers and loaders; empowered employees to become leaders through communication and management

EDUCATION

University Of Maryland Global Campus - Remote

August 2022 - Present

Bachelor's in Computer Science, GPA: 3.2

General Assembly | Remote

Software Engineering Immersive

February 2022 - May 2022

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

Prince George's Community College | Largo, MD

August 2019- May 2021

Associates of Science in Computer Science, GPA: 3.0